<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yeji Kim-Barros</title>
    <description>Compassionate leadership</description>
    <link>https://kimbarros.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://kimbarros.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:50:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:50:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the Point of One-on-one Meetings?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to think one-on-one meetings were tedious and ineffective. I used to shout into the void, “send it to me in an email! Or in slack! Stop wasting my time!” That is until I had two one-on-ones within a span of a month that made me reconsider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first revelation came after my manager, let’s call him “Kenny,” submitted his notice. My project wasn’t going well and team attrition and morale were dismal. I was miserable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was puzzled as I headed into my final one-on-one with Kenny. Our usual agenda of status updates and silent head nods didn’t seem like a good use of our time. But having some parting thoughts from an outgoing manager seemed beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenny kicked it off. “The stakeholders don’t like you. As a product manager, you need to be the glue for the project. You should be more personable. If I were you, I’d take them out for drinks. Hope all goes well with your future endeavors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was speechless. I ended our relationship with a curt, “okay, I’ll think about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I realized the following: First, one-one-ones are tedious, ineffective, &lt;em&gt;and cruel&lt;/em&gt;. Second, it’s better to have one-on-ones without a paper trail. This way, you’ve got plausible deniability of your cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new boss, let’s call him “Neal,” came in and started holding meet-and-greets with his teams and stakeholders. Bitter, broken, and dejected, I put off talking to Neal alone for as long as I could. I thought, “He heard the feedback already. He’s gonna hear what I have to say as a pathetic excuse. I need to have a win to debunk the hearsay. I’ll avoid him until then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This maneuver only lasted a few weeks after he settled in. He scheduled a one-on-one with me which threw me into full panic mode. Days leading up to the meeting, I penned what I would say so I wouldn’t sound defensive. I also repeated to myself how I wouldn’t bring up the elephant in the room unless he broached it first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head Game:&lt;/strong&gt; Your anxiety and paranoia are steering you in the right direction. People &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; easily swayed into believing everything they hear &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; they talk badly about you. Always. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Reality:&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Pronia is when you feel like people are conspiring to cheer you on and help you succeed. The fact of the matter is, the world isn’t quite black and white. No good or bad. But for every awful person setting off your paranoia, there’s someone who’s in your court. Seek those people out instead. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I launched into a project status update, per usual. I can’t remember the exact word-vomit, but it was something like, “The project is behind schedule. We’ve hit unforeseen complexities with…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No. I heard what others had to say. What’s going on?” I went off script. “Stakeholders don’t like me. This project isn’t going well.” At that moment, I thought, “Screw it. I can find another job.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How are you feeling?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” This was a foreign question to me, and I didn’t know how to answer it. At the time I thought, “I’m wiping away tears like a schoolgirl. In front of a new boss. Who only knows me through negative feedback. And I all but confirmed it to be true. He’s either dumb or satisfying some weird power move. I feel like utter shit. What do you think?” He glanced at me, waited for a beat, and started to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If one person can cause a project to spiral, then it’s not set up very well, is it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head Game:&lt;/strong&gt; If you drop the ball, the team will fail. People will blame you. That’s why 8-hour work day isn’t enough, and you have to be a team player. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Reality:&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a team effort. From those who are executing to those who manage and lead. Everyone has a role to play, but the burden and responsibility must be shared. If it isn’t, it’s an organizational issue. So a be a team player, sign off, and prioritize your mental health. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neal glossed over his rhetorical question, got up to the whiteboard, and motioned me to do the same. He asked me to draw concentric circles of stakeholders. The most vocal stakeholders went in the center circle. The least vocal individuals occupied the outer edges. He tasked himself with the same exercise. With his circles, the most influential individuals—the decision makers, the one who controls the budget—made up the core. The least influential members surrounded the outer rim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2022/concentric.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notes on concentric circles of influence and voice in an organization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explained that comparing our two sets of concentric circles will help us understand if we are listening to the right people. Neal also informed me that the chart should identify who should be talking with whom. “We can visualize actual versus perceived influence. Then you and I can divide and conquer to win people over at different levels of the organization. That’s how we’ll get our project in a better state.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one-on-ones following our meet-and-greet mirrored this format. He would first ask me what was going on. Then he would ask how I was feeling. We would then jump to constructive brainstorming followed by action items assigned to both of us. Often, Neal would check his notes and follow up on where we last left off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks in, he brought up how “work is no different than high school with cliques and bullies sometimes. It would help to get to know the people you’re working with outside of work. Only if you’re comfortable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then don’t. That’s fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the same suggestion that Kenny had brought up mere weeks ago. Only, with Neal, it didn’t seem so dissatisfying. I didn’t feel indignant. He respected the boundaries I set for myself without judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a conversation with Kenny, who I thought knew me well, I felt alone and worthless. But after a conversation with Neal, who didn’t know me at all, I felt supported, cared for, and respected. With Neal, I learned that you don’t have to know the individual personally to support and coach them. Compassion and care is all you need to get going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head Game:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to know your direct report personally in order to best support, help, and coach. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Reality:&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to know someone personally to want the best for them. You just have to care. This also means you don’t have to be friends with your direct reports or colleagues to wish them the best and help them grow. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reclaimed my time, voice, and confidence in one-on-ones with Neal, we seldom had tactical “shop” talk. Status updates became irrelevant; he trusted me to make the right day-to-day decisions. Instead, our time together became a chance to exchange, expand, and align on our thoughts about the team vision, strategy, and our roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, &lt;em&gt;just send it to me in an email&lt;/em&gt; is still very much my de facto sentiment for most meetings. Email, Slack, and Team messages help winnow the simple exchanges. One-on-ones are then left with private, thought-provoking conversations. Or serve as a much-needed intermission to catch a breath and chat about something silly. With the right approach, one-on-ones can be the best opportunity for both parties to learn, grow, and care for one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a story about a one-on-one gone right? Or wrong? &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reach out and share&lt;/a&gt; them with me. I’d love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/why-have-one-on-one-meetings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/why-have-one-on-one-meetings</guid>
        
        <category>Story</category>
        
        <category>Relationships</category>
        
        
        <category>Story</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Be a First-time Manager</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Your hard work has paid off, and you’re now a first-time manager. Hurray! It’s an exciting, nerve-racking transition. It’s also mired with uncertainty and doubt as you navigate this journey. And chances are, you haven’t received formal training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you become a good first-time manager? Here are seven tips based on my experience. If you have any other helpful tips, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;please reach out&lt;/a&gt;. I’d love to exchange thoughts and chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;really-listen&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; listen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetings have always bombarded my schedule, and I typically hear enough to engage. It’s low effort but it works because people love hearing themselves. Don’t do this with your direct reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing is passive. Listening is active. Take the words at face value. Pause before interpreting, judging, or evaluating. Stop letting your mind run towards what you’ll say in response. Stop hearing, start listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My direct report once told me they were stressed from my micromanagement. I had a ton of thoughts scurry past me at 100 mph: “What the hell? I hate micromanagers. I’ve never asked them what they do with their day. Have they even met other micromanagers? I’ll respond with, ‘I hear you, but I don’t understand,’ so they don’t feel like I’m dismissing this completely. Wonder what they’re actually unhappy with instead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, I micromanaged. I would’ve known sooner if I listened. It took their leave and another year for me to realize I messed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ask-exploratory-questions&quot;&gt;Ask exploratory questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking questions pairs so well with active listening. Ask questions to better understand your direct reports’ intentions. Be a fact-finder. Be an investigator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a good investigator is a great way to find customer problems to solve as a product manager. Being a good investigator allows for greater understanding and empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same applies to being a people manager. Probe to understand motives and thought processes instead of actions and execution processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Try this:&lt;/mark&gt; Instead of asking “What are you prioritizing?” ask: “How are you thinking through prioritization?” This provides you with informative data points and opportunities for more dialogues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How they prioritize tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How they perceive their contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How well you’ve conveyed your expectations, goals, and the vision.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Segue to align on prioritization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check and balance workload and care for your direct reports’ mental health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;convey-your-thoughts-simply&quot;&gt;Convey your thoughts simply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had to read Ernest Hemingway in high school, I found it a chore. How did he become a respected writer? By stitching together common words into short sentences? Balderdash! A complete gobbledygook! A disparaging example of American literature! The inner critic in me thought he had zero flourish and bland rhetoric. Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Any damn fool can make something complex; it takes a genius to make something simple.” &lt;cite&gt;― Pete Seeger ―&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much more difficult to be concise and profound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop practicing the art of bullshitting. Use short sentences to introduce and share your thoughts. Make it easy to skim your writing. Consider the key pieces of information you want to convey before you communicate. It’s okay to say “I need to think about this more.” That’s a complete thought. There’s no reason to improvise in hopes you stumble into brilliant prose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-trying-to-keep-score&quot;&gt;Stop trying to keep score&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read any relationship article on tallying up and you’ll get the same answer: Stop. Stop tallying up when you were right and they were wrong. Stop tallying up when they’ve made mistakes. Stop tallying up all the late nights you’ve put in and they didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s natural to notice and compare. It’s human to keep score for the nonsensical game you’re playing in your head. For me, it’s an act of self preservation. I’m the hero in my story. And I can prove my title is well-deserved. Look at my scoreboard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with people management, it’s not about you. It’s certainly not you versus your direct report. What do you get by having a higher score than your direct report? You can bask in the fact that you’re right and they’re wrong. What a shoddy employee, you think. Who is their lousy manager? Well done. You played yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-your-job-to-make-their-job-easier&quot;&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; job to make &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; job easier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, managers often promote high performing individual contributors. Those contributors becoming first-time managers need to be extra cautious. Excelling at your old job doesn’t mean you’ll excel at managing others who now do that job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a good chef doesn’t guarantee that you’ll run a restaurant well. In fact, &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; being a good chef may be a restaurateur’s downfall. So if you’re like me and you’ve thought about running a food truck because you make mean braised short ribs, you may want to reconsider. For one, I hate driving big cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go from contributor to manager, your job is no longer confined to what you used to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: As a software developer, you need to produce quality code. As a manager, you need to help software developers produce quality code. Your job as a manager isn’t exclusive to reviewing their lines of code. You need to figure out how to unblock and foster creativity in your team. You need to make sure the team understands what they’re working towards and why. You need to speak up on your team’s behalf to ensure they feel heard if their work looks risky ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hold-yourself-accountable-first&quot;&gt;Hold yourself accountable first&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was wrong. I’m sorry.” Do these statements stir a visceral reaction? They do for me. One of my high school coaches once told me “It’s sad and funny to see you deny how wrong you are.” He was a jerk. But he was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually got used to saying these phrases for all the wrong reasons. They were a Get Out of Jail Free Card. I could maintain a veneer of humility by raising my hand and taking responsibility. Afterwards, I would slither away from the situation and receive praise for being open, honest, and brave. They were my ultimate deus ex machina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is plain manipulation. What you do &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; your words carries greater weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Try this:&lt;/mark&gt; The team made a mistake? Complete an introspection with yourself before demanding to know what happened. Here are some questions to help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where were you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was your participation like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did the team feel during the project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was your pulse on the progress leading up to the mistake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can you help set the next project up for success?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to breed distrust as a first-time manager is blowing sycophantic, apologetic kisses upward and throwing “bring me solutions, not problems” accountability punches downward. It’s &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; team. Help them navigate out of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-be-a-jerk&quot;&gt;Don’t be a jerk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saved the most obvious for last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a first-time manager is like cultivating any relationship. You don’t want to be friends with an Arrogant Adam who doesn’t listen, Talkative Tanner who talks &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; you, or Forgetful Frank who says, “Sorry, I thought I already gave you money for the bill we split” after drinking 3 more drinks than you (Every. Week. And &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; no Venmo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, you don’t want to be managed by an Arrogant Adam who tells you how to do it his way and never accepts new ideas, Talkative Tanner who still insists on talking at you, or Forgetful Frank who says, “Sorry, I thought that you would be happy with this expanded responsibility and we agreed you aren’t yet ready for the next level” after 3 glowing performance reviews without tangible, actionable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Try this:&lt;/mark&gt; My self-assessment on whether I’m a jerk manager is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will this meeting/project/email/presentation help me?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will this meeting/project/email/presentation help my team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an easier time coming up with answers to question 1 versus 2, you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be acting like a jerk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/how-to-be-a-first-time-manager</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/how-to-be-a-first-time-manager</guid>
        
        <category>How-to</category>
        
        <category>Communication</category>
        
        <category>Relationships</category>
        
        
        <category>How-to</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
