<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yeji Kim-Barros</title>
    <description>The Product Person</description>
    <link>https://kimbarros.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://kimbarros.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 14:41:45 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 14:41:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Anatomy of a Breakthrough&quot; book summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anatomy of a Breakthrough&lt;/em&gt; describes what it means to be stuck and ways to break free from stagnation to achieve breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting stuck is inevitable. Learn to embrace stuck moments as opportunities for growth by adopting strategies to control your emotions, thoughts, and actions to become unstuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-be-stuck-is-to-be-human&quot;&gt;To be stuck is to be human&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often find themselves stuck but it’s usually hidden from our sight because we overtly broadcast the triumphant breakthroughs and wins. To free yourself, you need to acknowledge when you’re stuck and adopt strategies to master your emotional responses, apply the right mental models, and act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;many-get-stuck-in-the-middle&quot;&gt;Many get stuck in the middle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people start working toward a goal, they start quickly. And as people get closer to the goal, the speed up, too (known as the goal gradient effect). This means people usually get stuck in the middle of their goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate the middle. &lt;strong&gt;Break down large tasks&lt;/strong&gt; in the middle into smaller, manageable, achievable goals to prevent the lulls. Treat yourself when you reach these intermediate milestones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plateaus will occur. &lt;strong&gt;Vary the approaches&lt;/strong&gt; on how to work through the middle of the goal by embracing new strategies when old ways no longer deliver results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the first blush of difficulty, &lt;strong&gt;carry on&lt;/strong&gt;. Getting unstuck almost always takes a little longer than we expect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tame-the-anxiety&quot;&gt;Tame the anxiety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being stuck leaves us feeling trapped and anxious. Often, high levels of anxiety and perfectionism hinder progress and creativity. Learn to fail well by pausing and removing the pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reframe&lt;/strong&gt; the threats and hardships as challenges, like a slightly more intense rainbow road on Mario Kart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice radical acceptance. Instead of visualizing your success, &lt;strong&gt;imagine the worst-case scenario&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not so bad, right?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High standards can leave you feeling demotivated and hinder creativity. Don’t try to maximize everything and &lt;strong&gt;opt for good enough&lt;/strong&gt; (satisfice).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adopt a progressive definition of success&lt;/strong&gt;. Start low and increase the standards for success if you don’t want to “settle for lower standards”—though there’s nothing wrong with that, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mental-models-to-get-unstuck&quot;&gt;Mental models to get unstuck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Counterintuitively, &lt;strong&gt;apply constraints to free yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. This lessens the ego depletion and minimizes decision fatigue. For example, write a six-word memoir. Mine would be, “Wait a minute, I was trafficked?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice &lt;strong&gt;addition by subtraction&lt;/strong&gt;. The old adage of “Keep It Simple Stupid” works. Example: instead of adding training wheels for toddlers to learn how to balance themselves on a bike, balance bikes removed the pedals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brand new ideas are overrated. Instead, try to &lt;strong&gt;combine two or three existing ideas&lt;/strong&gt;. This can also apply in an organization where you combine different people on the team. Diversity is valuable for removing redundant ideas and thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t get too attached to your early ideas&lt;/strong&gt;. Studies show in an ideation session, creative ideas tend to improve and/or remain towards the second half of the session. This is known as the creative cliff illusion. This is because the obvious rarely produces good results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relying on a single skill or approach can lead to vulnerability when challenges arise. &lt;strong&gt;Stay curious and build a diverse set of skills and resources&lt;/strong&gt; to provide a safety net for getting unstuck. You can do this by crowdsourcing opinions, having a conversation with yourself and playing devil’s advocate, browsing rather than searching, and keeping a journal of facts and ideas that puzzle you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-do-it&quot;&gt;Just do it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore and experiment first, then execute&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll know which phase you’re mentally at by your responses. Are you saying yes to most incoming opportunities? Then you’re in the exploration and experimentation phase. Are you saying no? Then you’re in the execution phase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t learn by reading everything, but by figuring out which parts you don’t have to read. &lt;strong&gt;Figure out shortcuts&lt;/strong&gt; you can take in the beginning of your exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wander to inspire&lt;/strong&gt; creativity. Literally and figuratively. Changing where you’re working, getting up and moving, and performing fluid dances can assist with divergent thinking. Equally, allowing your mind to wander can free you up to consider creative ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-dose on actions. &lt;strong&gt;Build habits&lt;/strong&gt; and do a bite-sized action every day so you don’t get stuck as often.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use nouns to describe your actions&lt;/strong&gt; to deepen the association. For example: instead of saying, “I run,” say, “I’m a runner.” The former is an action you’re doing but the latter defines your identity based on your actions. The latter tends to promote greater consistency and habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/anatomy-of-a-breakthrough-book-summary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/anatomy-of-a-breakthrough-book-summary</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Book-summary</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;Mom Test&quot; book summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mom Test&lt;/em&gt; outlines rules for crafting good user conversations so that even your mom can give you objectively helpful insights about what you’re building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good questions elicit answers that are grounded in concrete facts about our customers’ lives, world views, and actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad questions do not. They can instead lead to false positives which lead you to build the wrong thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-rules-for-good-conversations&quot;&gt;5 rules for good conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk less and listen more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about their life instead of your idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask about the specifics from their past instead of generics, opinions, and hypotheticals about the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask them to do a task to see where the problems really are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End every conversation with, “Who else should I talk to?” If someone doesn’t want to make intros, that’s cool, too. You’ve learned that you’re either screwing up the meeting (probably by being too formal, pitchy, or clingy) or they don’t actually care about the problem you’re solving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-questions&quot;&gt;Good questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why is this a problem for you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When is the last time this problem affected you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to me through the last time this happened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did you try to fix it then?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did you bother doing it this way?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How are you dealing with it now?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What else have you tried?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much did you spend on solution X?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What feature did you find most or least helpful from solution X?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did you want the feature?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re no longer using solution X, how are you currently coping without the feature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bad-questions-elicit&quot;&gt;Bad questions elicit…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Niceties&lt;/strong&gt;. “What do you think about my product?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions&lt;/strong&gt;. “What do you think about a product which does X?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypotheticals&lt;/strong&gt;. “Would you buy this?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future promises&lt;/strong&gt;. “Will you sign up for the beta test when we launch?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-these-with-a-grain-of-salt&quot;&gt;Take these with a grain of salt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, these are ego-boosting remarks that reaffirm your bias towards what you’re building without any concrete validations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliments&lt;/strong&gt;. They’re the fool’s gold of customer learning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluffs&lt;/strong&gt;. These may lead to confirmation bias.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Generic: “I usually, always, or never…”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Future-looking: “I would” or “I will”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hypothetical: “I could” or “I might”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; Some problems don’t actually matter. Some people are complainers, not customers; they want their petty annoyances of their day solved, but won’t have done anything to fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/mom-test.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mock conversation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is a paraphrased exchange I had with someone. I didn’t pursue this problem further.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-conversations&quot;&gt;Finding conversations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may start with cold calls, but the goal is to turn them into warm intros. Two ways of finding conversations include you going to them and bringing them to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going to them:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cold calls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seizing the moment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through mutual friends and colleagues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding a good excuse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being in the right place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing them to you:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organizing meetups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speaking and teaching&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting creative in attracting attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example on getting creative: I love using my fountain pens and calligraphy pens for journaling my thoughts. I purposefully went into a co-working space, made ink swatches, and started journaling in the cafeteria until people started getting curious and asking why I’m watching my inks dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/creative-bait.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My ink swatches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/mom-test-book-summary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/mom-test-book-summary</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Book-summary</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I don&apos;t want to be a wannapreneur</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time someone told me they wanted to break away from the corporate rat race to be their own boss, I would be able to afford a home &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an avocado toast for breakfast. If I had another dollar for every time someone told me they had a unicorn idea in their head that’s ready for takeoff, I would master the art of quiet luxury fashion completely from head to toe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I applied for a founder residency program at Antler, a “day zero investor.” For the interview preparation, I’ve spent most of my time thinking about my fit above all else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for 2023 was always twofold: establish a consistent stream of income and start working on an idea I’m passionate about. But as the sage Ron Swanson once said, you shouldn’t half ass two things and whole ass one thing instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So am I in the right frame of mind to actually commit to working on my idea wholly or is this a fleeting wannapreneurship fever dream? To evaluate myself, I completed a SWIL analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swil-analysis&quot;&gt;SWIL analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My SWIL analysis (stands for &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;trengths, &lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;eaknesses, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;ncentives and &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;imitations) borrows from the SWOT analysis framework. Unlike SWOT, where the analysis is done by identifying both internal and external factors, I used SWIL to look inwardly at myself to determine the impact I can make and the viability of me working on a new startup idea. As such, opportunities and threats are replaced with incentives and limitations, where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incentives describe my values and motivations, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limitations describe my personal limitations and situations that may hinder my progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/swil-draft.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Brain dump&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;First draft was a brain dump&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/swil-analysis.png&quot; alt=&quot;My organized SWIL notes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is my organized SWIL notes. You can read it in full &lt;a href=&quot;https://whimsical.com/swil-analysis-PQM4KFoVGxpC1AmMBEABmS@2Ux7TurymMx2YpkpxqR7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge I had was defining my values. The process of introspection felt confusing; I often didn’t know how to differentiate between certain values. I’m still not sure I picked the right ones. To do this, I borrowed from &lt;a href=&quot;https://brenebrown.com/hubs/dare-to-lead/&quot;&gt;Dr. Brown’s body of work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object data=&quot;assets/pdf/list-of-values.pdf&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; type=&quot;application/pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;takeaway&quot;&gt;Takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I recognized that my bias for action led to achieving consistent stream of income. But by exerting my time, energy, and focus towards this goal, I’ve shown two classic signs of a wannapreneur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constant idea generation with commitment issues&lt;/strong&gt; where I don’t stick with one idea for long. I keep brainstorming new concepts as I talk to people and it’s been awhile since I’ve taken steps towards execution beyond prototype testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No concrete plans with inconsistent efforts&lt;/strong&gt; around execution. All my executive functioning skills are used up for consulting and business development. Working on my idea has been too sporadic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m going to take the first step to address this issue by going whole ass on executing against my idea; I’m joining Antler for their fall cohort. If you’re also interested in this thought exercise before you make the jump to something scary and exciting, try this and let me know how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/avoiding-wannapreneurship</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/avoiding-wannapreneurship</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Personal-essay</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pivoting direction without a single line of code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was determined and inspired by the vision of creating meaningful connections and combating the pervasive issue of loneliness. Instead of building a solution, I defined the target audience and what problem I wanted to solve. This led me to conversations with potential early adopters to explore their needs and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, I went old school: Markers, crayons, pen, and paper to create paper prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the testing phase, I stumbled upon a different problem, leading me to reevaluate my original direction. I want to share my journey of product discovery, insights gained from my exploration, and why I made the decision to pivot away from my initial idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chasing-and-validating-my-north-star&quot;&gt;Chasing and validating my north star&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of my vision was the desire to build a platform that fostered authentic human connections and helped individuals combat the profound sense of loneliness prevalent in today’s digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I believed that remote workers would be the ideal early adopters for my platform. With the increasing number of workers transitioning to remote setups, the traditional water cooler conversations that often foster friendships were fading away. I saw an opportunity to bridge the gap and create a sense of local connection among remote workers. However, as I engaged with potential users and tested my prototypes, I discovered a more pressing problem that most remote workers faced: the utility of networking for securing new job opportunities or acquiring clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-misalignment-and-the-decision-to-pivot&quot;&gt;The misalignment and the decision to pivot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This revelation forced me to address the misalignment between the problem I uncovered and my vision of combating loneliness through meaningful relationships. While the networking issue was urgent and had its own merits, it didn’t directly address the deeper issue I initially set out to solve. This realization prompted me to reevaluate my direction and consider the insights from the references I had explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the misalignment, I found myself at a crossroads: should I pivot towards the new, “hair on fire” problem or stay true to my original vision of combatting loneliness through meaningful connections? Ultimately, my true passion lies in authentic connections and addressing the core issue of loneliness; pursuing a different problem would dilute my purpose and impact. So I decided to pivot away from my idea to realign with my core mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giving-up-perseverance-and-staying-grounded&quot;&gt;Giving up, perseverance, and staying grounded&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reads like an admission of defeat. After all, I’m left with receipts from Starbucks gift cards, paper prototypes, and a declaration that I’m putting an end to my current endeavor by pivoting away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I see this as a big win for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love the hero’s journey who triumphs through it all. Their unwavering grit, tenacity, and perseverance against adversity. But spotting the unworkable that lies somewhere between your dreams, fears, and reality is a valuable trait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I conclude another chapter on what some may call failure, I’m going to embrace the valuable lessons learned, the insights gained, and the resilience that drives me forward. And remind myself: while it feels like I’m a failure now, this will lead to a different opportunity to create something truly impactful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure isn’t a final destination. It’s just a stepping stone on the path to growth and discovery. And by letting go, I can open up and shape my journey in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/pivoting-on-an-idea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/pivoting-on-an-idea</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Personal-essay</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A story on differentiation gone wrong</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m something of a hobby collector. One of my hobbies includes a “product &amp;amp; design journal.” It includes product and design decisions I see in the wild, and I dissect them. I recently encountered an interesting situation involving an e-commerce store I frequently shop at, and I wanted to explore it in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1-the-legacy-of-brand-loyalty&quot;&gt;Part 1: The legacy of brand loyalty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, my father-in-law was struggling with foot pain and asked for a Tylenol to alleviate his discomfort. My partner pulled out the bottle of generic brand acetaminophen from his parents’ cupboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, not this. I need a Tylenol.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explained, “That’s a brand name. The generic name for the medicine is acetaminophen. This is the same thing.” We all assumed he was frazzled from the pain, so I cracked a joke. “Kirkland is just its street name. It’s fresh from Costco.” Bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He insisted, “I understand. But Tylenol is different. It’s better.” We ended up bringing home an extra-large bottle of unopened acetaminophen that day. And to this day, he remains loyal to Tylenol and refuses to use any other brand (though, this isn’t completely true. But you can ask me in person for the rest of this story so I can have some plausible deniability with my mischiefs managed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-2-the-rise-of-category-loyalty&quot;&gt;Part 2: The rise of category loyalty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My shopping habits seem like the polar opposite from my father-in-law at first glance. I drink La Croix, Spindrift, Poland Spring, San Pellegrino, Perrier, or Polar when I want sparkling water. Even as a skincare fan, my choice of cleanser is the generic one I can get in bulk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am loyal to are product categories. I’ll buy sparkling water, but you won’t see me with root beers in my cart. I go through mild, oil-based cleansers in the blink of an eye, but no makeup remover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The way we shop has shifted from brand or store loyalty to category loyalty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re living in the era of plenty: There’s no shortage of information. We can look up product features, shop for the best prices, and look at product reviews. There’s no shortage of product variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/wayfair-trash.png&quot; alt=&quot;Number of trash bins available for sale on Wayfair&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;For example: my trash bin lid broke, so I need a new bin for the kitchen. On Wayfair, there are 3,823 products matching my category.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as more of us embrace our inner Judas and Benedict Arnold, what can companies do? Differentiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-3-differentiation-gone-wrong&quot;&gt;Part 3: Differentiation gone wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the board gaming community, many enthusiasts prefer to support independent game stores run by hobbyists. This is one category where I make exceptions about long lead times and higher free shipping thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, even in this niche market, store loyalty is not guaranteed. Recently, one of the stores I support, boardlandia.com, introduced “Boardlandia VIP” – a $110/year subscription service that offers exclusive sales and the ability to jump the queue for shipping, customer service, and new product alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the intention to differentiate was novel, it didn’t hit the core components of successful differentiation. Two key elements were missing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique or compelling product value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The membership doesn’t provide clear value to the customer. It doesn’t solve a specific customer problem or provide an enhanced experience. Furthermore, board games are not a product that consumers typically need urgently. Deep discounts on MSRP can be found on other competing websites without a monthly installment; it’s unclear whether VIP-exclusive sales are substantially different from what other sites offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fostering a strong relationship and community building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a sense of community through social media, events, and memberships helps to bolster loyalty. Similarly, exceptional customer service creates stronger relationships. Another online game store I frequently visit, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopmerchant.com/&quot;&gt;tabletopmerchant.com&lt;/a&gt;, provides handwritten, personalized notes with each order. Every order is impeccably packed to satisfy the inner collector in us and leave our gaming boxes in pristine condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/tm-letter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My latest letter from owners of Tabletop Merchant from my last order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Boardlandia’s VIP membership plan creates a divide between the “haves” and “have-nots” to create their community and bolster their relationships with their customers. While $110 a year may be a small amount for some, it’s a steep price for a hobby that’s already pricey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-4-what-can-be-done&quot;&gt;Part 4: what can be done?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a typical product person, I would say that the answer depends on the problem that needs solving. Assuming the company is trying to explore new monetization paths, a successful subscription-based business for a brick-and-mortar storefront can provide a larger financial safety net with its monthly recurring revenue (MRR) generation. If the subscription takes off, it will certainly become a key differentiator for the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this to work, the company must first figure out how to create a successful subscription plan. If I were in their shoes, that’s the first part of the playbook I’d review: What are the necessary customer values that must be met for the membership to make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the goal is to foster greater affinity and loyalty, launching a “retail as a service” VIP membership may not have been my first choice. This is not to say that it should not be explored, but there are smaller bets I’d consider first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the company is convinced that the membership plan is a valid revenue stream, it would have made a bigger and more positive impact if customers were able to see the tangible value first. For example, they could have introduced a membership-only sale on their page, with the option for customers to add the membership to their cart if they want to purchase games at a steep discount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the common denominator between the two approaches is the same. &lt;strong&gt;It all circles back to the customer. What do they value? How much are they willing to spend on it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The silver lining is that three hours after the original VIP membership launch email, the company followed up with another email acknowledging the disappointing feedback from the community and adjusted their benefits. The adjustments don’t address the fundamental gaps in value offering still, but I’m optimistic after seeing their quick reaction to the community’s feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/differentiation-gone-wrong</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/differentiation-gone-wrong</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Personal-essay</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        <category>Product-management</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am going slow to go fast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Going fast and breaking things has become a ubiquitous phrase in product management, akin to the widely adopted Agile Manifesto. In fact, there are so many variations of this mindset. Fail fast and learn faster. Speed is a currency. Time to market is everything. Iterate quickly. Rapid prototyping. And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this need for speed, I’ve seen a lot of shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“You don’t need to talk to the users. Our team is the voice of the customer, and we’ve collected NPS results already.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We have to be agile. Start making some bets, build, and ship something so we can start learning.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Our competitors have already built it this way. This is the industry standard, and we’re already behind. If we don’t have the resources, I’ll find consultants on UpWork.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These aren’t truly agile, nor are they failing fast in order to learn and iterate. They’re just failing. It just feels palatable because it’s justified with Silicon Valley phrases and complete disregard for the survivorship bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temptations to justify and succumb to the shortcuts are high. Even as I work on my personal project, I need to intentionally suppress the urges to skip the discovery process and beeline to a conclusion to show the world I’ve made meaningful, impressive progress: a &lt;em&gt;visible, tangible&lt;/em&gt; progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My antidote to meaningfully slowing down and appreciating the process is to reflect on the frequent shortcuts that have plagued my product development processes in the past. By doing so, I can take proactive steps to prevent these skips from occurring and ensure a more successful outcome for my current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, these are the steps that are frequently cut in a product development process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;: research and understanding user problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User testing and iterative design&lt;/strong&gt;: designing; testing through product validation with real users on the usability, functionality, and user experience; and refining the product in multiple iterations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QA and testing&lt;/strong&gt;: testing the product for quality and ensuring that it meets requirements and specifications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation and postmortem analysis:&lt;/strong&gt; analyzing the iteration, identifying areas of learning and improvement, and documenting for reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my current project, I’m straddling between the discovery, user testing, and iterative design phases. I’ve been feeling self-conscious when asked, “So you don’t have a concrete solution?” or, “So you’ve just been talking to people?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my pep talk I give myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I chose not to skip the discovery phase despite being told that “building a product is all about making bets.” Making product bets isn’t a shorthand to forgo the discovery phase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making bets not about declaring, “This is my belief. It may or may not work, and I’m going to bet on it to find out.” Instead it’s, “Here are all the potential possibilities of how this might shake out, and based on some limited information I have, I’m going to go down this path.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The discovery phase allows me to take calculated risks. The discovery phase increases the odds of winning the bets I make.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an invisible step to many, but it’s an important step for me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living up to a core set of values is difficult. I’m often struggling to stick to them. I’m tempted daily to dismiss and downplay the discovery work I’ve done over the past three months because I don’t have a tangible product to show for it. Perhaps you feel the same way as you build out your product or your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I want to acknowledge and appreciate all the failed paper prototypes and ideas I’ve scrapped along the way, as they have refined my betting process and brought me closer to a viable solution: thank you, failures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/going-slow-to-go-fast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/going-slow-to-go-fast</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Personal-essay</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        <category>Product-management</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case study on a 4-step process towards problem discovery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal is to help people practice self-care in a meaningful way. However, before diving into product ideas, I needed to address several unknowns and assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What exactly is self-care?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do people define self-care, both broadly and for themselves?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do people explicitly practice self-care?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there a significance in “meaningful” self-care?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we practice self-care meaningfully?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, I sought to understand self-care from other people’s perspectives. I followed four steps: research, define, chat, and refine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out with very simple search terms on &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholar.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt; to find more comprehensive, specialized information, primary and secondary sources, and related research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/google-scholar-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;My first Google Scholar search term was &amp;quot;self care&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this exercise, I discovered many studies completed on self-care. For example, I found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0885392422004699&quot;&gt;recent study from Journal of Pain and Symptom Management&lt;/a&gt; that examined the correlations among self-care, emotion regulation, social support, and well-being among young adults during the COVID pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge was knowing when to stop this step and move to the next one. To mitigate, I gave myself a maximum of two days to explore and research before moving to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;define&quot;&gt;Define&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I identified recurring themes as I read academic journals and books on the topic. To keep track of my findings, I kept a research repository using Notion, where I recorded my takeaways, more details on the findings, and “key terms,” or words that frequently appeared in my readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/research-repo.png&quot; alt=&quot;My research repository in Notion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge was avoiding jumping to conclusions too soon. With reputable sources presenting multiple convincing findings, it was all too easy to get sidetracked and end up with numerous product ideas sprouting in every direction like dandelions in springtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/mind-map.png&quot; alt=&quot;My mind map of ideas&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;My haphazard web of self-care ideas during the process.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this step, I gathered up my write ups and key terms, noted key observations and reactions, and defined my hypothesis statements. This exercise led me to some unexpected realizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While I expected self-care to be strongly linked to mindfulness, self-reflection, and stress management, I found that routines and habits played a more significant role than I anticipated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contrary to my assumption that self-esteem would play a significant role in self-care, I discovered that self-compassion was a more common theme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social support and prosocial activities also emerged as important means of caring for oneself, which reminded me of the Southern African philosophy of ubuntu: “a person is a person through other persons” or &lt;em&gt;umuntu ngumuntu ngabantu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/word-cloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;Word cloud of frequent &amp;quot;key terms&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these realizations, I formed several hypotheses and assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practicing routine self-care activities are more impactful than one-off “abortive treatments.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When it comes to self-care, people are more attuned to “abortive treatments” to stop feeling bad as negative emotions are happening instead of “routine treatments” to become more resilient.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practicing self-compassion is a key component in practicing self-care.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practicing care for others can facilitate self-care.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People want a sense of connection and fulfillment, but they might not perceive this as a form of self-compassion or self-care.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How someone defines a sense of fulfillment can vary wildly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People want to practice self-care. But they don’t know how and are employing different ways to “feel good.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chat&quot;&gt;Chat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After developing initial hypotheses, I sought out people through channels like Meetup, Reddit, Discord, Lunchclub, local networking events, and speed friending events. Before each conversation, I defined 2-3 things I wanted to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with these two:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do people improve their emotional well-being in their daily lives?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do people start and maintain meaningful connections with others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent myself from making premature assumptions, I made a conscious effort to jot down direct quotes from my conversations with others and organized them on sticky notes in my Miro board. This was much more difficult with in-person conversations. I took multiple pauses to jot down notes during in-person conversations by saying, “Do you mind if I quickly write this down? I want to think more about what you just said,” before rapidly scribbling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the “chat” step was the most difficult for me. You need to find an audience. You need to ask the right questions. You need to listen. You need to be open-minded. You need a little chutzpah to approach people and ask them personal questions–which means you need to be  vulnerable, too. It would be wildly unfair to go into these conversations as an interrogator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The least obvious challenge was knowing when I had sufficient enough data to progress to the subsequent stage. To address this, I set up two criteria for myself. The first was when I began to hear similar responses from various individuals. The second was speaking with six people. Whichever condition I achieved first was a cue for me to move on. I made six the cutoff because having fewer participants would not offer a wide enough range of perspectives. On the other hand, talking to more people would require a significant investment of effort and time while providing diminishing returns on insights gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;refine&quot;&gt;Refine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this step, I refined my understanding and hypotheses by gathering takeaways from my conversations with people, just like the “define” step where I gathered takeaways from my readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this initial cycle of research-define-chat-refine, I had conversations with five people and gained valuable insights. These conversations highlighted that people crave “genuine, authentic, and meaningful” connections in their lives, but it’s challenging to find and sustain them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/findings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Snippet of my findings from conversations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using these insights, I was able to discover a problem and validate some of my hypotheses. For example, I started with the hypothesis that “people want a sense of connection and fulfillment, but they might not perceive this as a form of self-compassion or self-care.” This evolved into “Interconnectivity can improve self-compassion, fulfillment, and actualization. But people are afraid and ashamed of connecting and maintaining connection.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-am-i-now&quot;&gt;Where am I now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I established a weekly cadence of research-define-chat-refine, dedicating 1-2 days to each step. I documented my findings on separate Miro boards for each week, resulting in a total of five boards encompassing my problem discovery efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this iteration, I identified two key problems to further explore and develop solutions for. The first is how people can find interconnectivity while working a remote job so they don’t feel isolated and lonely. The second is how people can address the fear of rejection and shame often associated with forming and maintaining bonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to go make another Miro board!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/case-study-on-problem-discovery</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/case-study-on-problem-discovery</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Case-study</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        <category>Product-management</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reasons why I am hesitant to share my ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I found myself scrolling through startup forums and noticed a common theme. People are notoriously protective of their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“My current concern is protecting my idea.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I have a really unique product idea, but I’m worried the big players will steal the product.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Should I copyright my idea before I approach investors?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Can I get people to sign an NDA before I start talking about my ideas?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it. I am, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read any of my previous blog posts, you’ll find something suspiciously missing in my journey through problem discovery. I don’t mention the product ideas I’m currently pursuing. Why? Fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fear or rejection: what if someone thinks my idea is terrible and shoots it down?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fear of failure: what if my idea doesn’t work out and I look like an idiot?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fear of judgment: what if someone tears my idea apart and thinks less of my skills and expertise?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the lizard brain and my defense kicking in, I know sharing ideas early and frequently is incredibly beneficial. By talking to other people, you can gain valuable insights and feedback that can help shape your idea into something more tangible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for idea thefts? Sure, you may be sitting on a revolutionarily unique idea (personally, this isn’t the case for me). But clever ideas still end up maturing in different forms. Ideas are a dime a dozen. Execution is everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as a means of talking the talk and walking the walk, I’ll lead by example and share my own hypotheses and problem discovery work from the past month as a case study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/protecting-new-ideas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/protecting-new-ideas</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>Personal-essay</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discovering hidden user insights (Part 2: how to talk to people)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended a local networking event to meet new people for my undercover problem discovery work. My primary goal was to get people talking and learn about their current struggles and how they’re trying to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, I asked a lot of questions. People’s faces lit up, eager to share more. I was met with, “I’m glad you asked.” Or “Now that you mention it…” And “Funny you ask because…” Someone proclaimed that this was the deepest conversation they had had in recent history. (I started by asking, “so what troubles you these days?”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to interrogate them in a one-sided conversation so I stopped asking. The roles reversed and they asked, “So what do you do?” I stumbled through my abstract. “I have a hard time being compassionate towards myself. I get very critical and it makes it difficult for me to practice self care. I want to see if this is a struggle shared by other people and see if there is a way to solve this problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oh wow, that’s interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s a tough problem to solve. Good luck with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well, good for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;🦗 🦗 🦗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/posts/2023/sad-monkey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a sad, awkward monkey staring down at the ground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-would-you-carry-the-conversation-from-here-on&quot;&gt;How would you carry the conversation from here on?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, there are four paths one can choose to take, in my order of preference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share how the problem affects me:&lt;/strong&gt; I can take a more casual approach and talk about how the problem I’m looking to solve affects my life. This could be a great opening to establish a connection and to get to know each other better, if they’re willing to reciprocate and empathize.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share my “why”:&lt;/strong&gt; I can expand on why I’m passionate about the problem I’m trying to solve. This could be another great way to build rapport and create a deeper connection without feeling like I’m building up to “the pitch.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share my process:&lt;/strong&gt; I can delve into my research and plans to tackle the problem. This could inspire ideas or creative solutions from unexpected sources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shuffle Away:&lt;/strong&gt; Change the topic, walk away, or if the conversation is still salvageable, put your undercover user researcher hat back on and continue asking questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most of my conversations last week, I reached option 4 within a few minutes and walked away. There were two reasons for this. Firstly, I wanted to respect their boundaries. Secondly, I interpreted the niceties as a lack of curiosity. It’s like dating: if they were genuinely interested, they would have been curious. If not, they weren’t interested in a meaningful way. That’s okay; I won’t force a conversation. However, there is another scenario to consider: maybe they didn’t know what to ask or how to keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ways-to-authentically-carry-a-conversation&quot;&gt;Ways to authentically carry a conversation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share first:&lt;/strong&gt; To build rapport and find common ground, start by sharing a personal anecdote to make the other person feel comfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…but don’t monopolize the conversation:&lt;/strong&gt; My general rule of thumb is, if I start to feel like &lt;em&gt;I’m&lt;/em&gt; getting too comfortable with my monologue, then I’ve gone on too long.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice active listening:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay attention to nonverbal cues when communicating face-to-face. You can mirror their body language, repeat what the other person has said, and ask follow-up questions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…and don’t be afraid of silences:&lt;/strong&gt; Active listening may not always mean you have a response ready. It’s okay to take a moment to think and process what the other person has said. A simple prompt like, “Tell me more,” can help you take the time you need without feeling uncomfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask open-ended questions&lt;/strong&gt;: Open-ended questions allow more detailed answers, while closed-ended questions can be answered simply: yes or no. Even questions asking for specific info are closed-ended; for example, “What do you do for a living?” and “How are you doing today?” Both start with “what” or “how”, but are closed-ended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/conversation-skills-for-user-research</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/conversation-skills-for-user-research</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>How-to</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        <category>Product-design</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discovering hidden user insights (Part 1: undercover user research)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To avoid the pitfall of making assumptions when developing a new product, I opted for some undercover user research instead of building first and then adding scientific rigor to validate my idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-undercover-user-research&quot;&gt;What’s undercover user research?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I engage in conversations with people without labeling them as user research. I ask open-ended questions to gain insight into people’s needs and problems. I also call this the Meijer method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who didn’t grow up in the Midwest, Meijer is a grocery store. As a moody teenager whose parents didn’t speak English fluently, one of my least favorite things was acting as a “meat shield” for my parents when people started engaging in conversations while waiting to check out at the supermarket. Midwesterners love to spill the beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; people to spill the beans. An informal conversation can be a cost-effective way to quickly gather insights. All that is required is the willingness to ask good questions and listen attentively for any valuable information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five steps to help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List 3 goals you want to achieve with your research:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with a key assumption or hypothesis you hold. Validate it by determining what must be true for the assumption to be accurate.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What do you want to learn about your users? What questions do you have about their behavior, needs, or motivations?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ensure your research goals are clear, so your research is focused and effective.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan your locations wisely:&lt;/strong&gt; Get creative and resourceful to find people to speak to. Consider places where you can observe or talk to real people, such as a coffee shop, a networking event, a social event, or even online through social media.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be authentic:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to be respectful and genuinely curious when engaging with someone else. Even if you have a goal in mind when entering a conversation, it should be based on genuine interest and an open-minded attitude. Don’t push the conversation; instead, just enjoy it. People often have an innate ability to detect if someone is not being genuine, spinning bullshit, or being too eager, so it’s important to be mindful of this and set aside research goals if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gather first-hand accounts:&lt;/strong&gt; Take notes whenever possible. It is best to write down &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what someone has told you, rather than your interpretation. Themes and patterns may become apparent after your second or third conversation. This could help you adjust how you ask questions and delve deeper. However, try to avoid analysis and focus on gathering first-hand accounts for now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draw insights and create new hypotheses:&lt;/strong&gt; Observe, reflect, and draw conclusions from your primary sources. By taking a step back and looking at the big picture, you’ll be able to uncover broader insights that you may have missed if you had focused too narrowly too soon. In doing so, you can generate new hypotheses, assumptions, and questions for the next iteration of research and discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://kimbarros.com/discovering-insights-through-user-research</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kimbarros.com/discovering-insights-through-user-research</guid>
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
        <category>How-to</category>
        
        <category>Founder</category>
        
        <category>Product-design</category>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
